Alie Brubaker

Newburgh, IN 763-269-1213 | findingalberta@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/alie-brubaker/ | github.com/AlbertaLynnBrubaker | medium.com/@findingalberta

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Building experience with Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming. Background in non-tech industries with many years of team leadership and goal-oriented metric achievement in retail consumables and sales. Primary focus in team-building and training. Very interested in working as a DEI ambassador or leader.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Trained with JavaScript and React, with Styled Components for styling, and Ruby on Rails using SQLite3.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Rainbow - Github

A social media site with an emphasis on being a place for LGBTQ+ people to gather and share their lives

- Constructed a Rails backend in a monorepo with a React frontend
- Implemented a React library to create an infinite scroll reverse engineered from class components for use in functional components
- Used the Bcrypt Ruby gem to create user authorization and authentication on client-side input
- Learned to use the JSON-API Serializer to streamline backend operation with Rails Active Storage
- Applied Active Storage to maintain a database table of user uploaded image files as avatars and posts
- Built a Facebook-like UI/UX in React using Styled-Components and React-Bootstrap

DnD Flatbase - Github - Frontend | Backend

A full stack web application for players of Dungeons & Dragons to create, store, and modify character sheets

- Leveraged Ruby using Active Record and Sinatra to build a back-end to store data in a SQL database
- Utilized React to build a very clean interface for the user with attractive features which mimic the DnDBeyond UX
- Handbuilt the styling for the UX in React with Styled-Components which created a sleek user experience

Flatify - Github

A close one-for-one UI clone of the Spotify web application

Constructed an extremely close homage to Spotify's signature look in React using Styled-Components

MixIt: A cocktail search engine - Github

A search engine for cocktails from a third-party API

- Experimented with vanilla JavaScript, vanilla CSS and HTML
- App is a single page application

EXPERIENCE

Toyota Motors Manufacturing Indiana

Princeton, IN

Production Team Member

06/2019 - 05/2022

- Installed parts on unibody vehicles in very fast paced manufacturing environment
- Focused on continuous improvement of process and error free production

Total Wine & More Wine Supervisor/M1

Minnetonka, MN

06/2016 - 04/2019

- Lead a top performing wine and spirits sales team across similar stores company wide
- Performed in manager role focusing on day-to-day operation
- Responsible for strong performing in-store public wine and spirits education

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Remote

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React program

06/2022 - 10/2022

University of Minnesota

Minneapolis, MN

Attended for five semesters

08/2004 - 05/2006